Guide to the Edward Northup Hay Papers 1914-1958
Edward Northup Hay Papers
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Edward Northup Hay Papers, 1914-1958
5227
Hay, Edward N.
5 linear ft.
Diaries, manuscripts (documents), photographs.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Consists of personal and family documents; materials relating to organizations with which Hay was professionally involved; and reference files concerning employee rating and testing.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Edward Northrup Hay was a management consultant, engineer, and personnel director; publisher and editor of the PERSONNEL JOURNAL; and founder and president of Hay and Associates, a management consultant firm. Hay also developed executive aptitude tests which he marketed through the Aptitude Test Service.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Consists of personal and family documents; materials relating to organizations with which Hay was professionally involved; and reference files concerning employee rating and testing.
SUBJECTS
Names:
American Gas Association; Ahern, Eileen; Bach, C. A. (Christian Albert), 1870-1942; Cardall, Alfred (Alfred J.); Harker, John B.; Hay, Edward N. (Edward Northrup), 1891-1958; King, Joseph E.; Kurtz, William F.; Raube, S. Avery; Wadsworth, Guy W., Jr.; Walters, J.E.; American Security and Trust Company; Aptitude Test Service; B.F. Goodrich Company; California Texas Oil Corporation; Central-Hanover Bank and Trust Company.; Crown Can Company; Edward N. Hay and Associates; F. W. Dodge Corporation; First National Bank of Boston; General Electric Company; General Motors Corporation; Granite Trust Company; Irving Trust Company; Life Insurance Company of Virginia; Pennsylvania Company for Banking and Trusts; Philadelphia Gas Works Company; Saco-Lowell Shops; Southern California Gas Company; United States. Office of Price Administration.; Vickers Incorporated
Subjects:
Personnel management--United States; Personnel management--Research; Personnel directors; Banks and banking. United States. Personnel management.; Executive ability. Testing.; Executives. Salaries, pensions, etc. United States.; White collar workers. United States. Ability testing.; World War, 1914-1918. Personal narratives.; World War, 1939-1945. Personal narratives.; Personnel management. United States.; Personnel management. Research.; Personnel directors.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Manuscripts (documents); Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related Collections:
/3051: Albert Martin Papers
5730: John H. Cornehlsen Papers
6255: Richard Sears Barrett Papers
CONTAINER LIST
- Family History (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Personal History (Box 1, Folder 2)
  includes photos
- Army Correspondence, 1917-1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Army Correspondence, 1914-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4-7)
- Hay Diary, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Hunting Club, 1945-1955 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Aptitude Test Service, 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Hay & Associates - Articles for Men and Management (Box 1, Folder 11)
  no date
- Hay & Associates - Clients, 1949-1957 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Hay & Associates - Correspondence, 1945-1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Hay & Associates - Financial, 1947-1956 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Hay & Associates - Men & Management, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
- Hay & Associates - Philadelphia City Rpy (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Hay & Associates - Phoenix Indemnity Co., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Hay & Associates - Sales Promotion, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Hay & Associates - Staff, 1947-1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Hay & Associates - Staff - Cardall I & II, 1943-1950 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
- Office of Price Administration - Correspondence & Memoranda, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Office of Price Administration - Manuals & Rates, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Pennsylvania Co. - Correspondence, 1934-1945 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Pennsylvania Co. - Policies & Procedures I & II, 1937-1950 (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
- Personnel Psychology, 1947-1955 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Personnel Journal - Articles to be written, 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Personnel Journal - Correspondence, 1947-1957 (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
- Reconstruction Fincance Corp., 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Salary Administration, 1947-1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Salary Administration - Material for Article, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Supervisory Development, 1946-1954 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Job Evaluation - Articles, 1943-1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Job Evaluation - Banking, 1946-1952 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Job Evaluation - Benge Manual of Procedures, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Job Evaluation - Clients, 1951-1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Job Evaluation - Descriptions, 1948-1951 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
- Job Evaluation - Factor Definitions (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Job Evaluation - General Electric, 1950-1956 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Job Evaluation - General Motors Job Manual (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Job Evaluation - Hay & Co. Articles, 1945-1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Job Evaluation - Hay Manual of Procedures, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Job Evaluation - Pennsylvania Co., 1934-1938 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Job Evaluation - Reliability, 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Job Evaluation - Reliability - Hay Articles, 1951-1957 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Job Evaluation - Statistical Methods, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Labor, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Merit Rating - Articles, 1941-1951 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Merit Rating - Industrial Psychology Inc, 1947-1953 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Merit Rating - Plans, 1940-1951 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Merit Rating - Rating Forms, 1948-1956 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Performance Rating, 1946-1951 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Personnel Journal - "Editor to Reader" (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Personnel Journal - Ideas for Articles, 1947-1957 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
- Personnel Journal - Misc. Reprints, 1947-1952 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Personnel Journal - Promotion, 1951-1957 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Testing - Activity Vector Analysis Study, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Testing - American Bankers Assn., 1950-1954 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
- Testing - American Gas Assn, 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Testing - Articles, 1943-1953 (Box 3, Folder 10-12)
- Testing - Briggs - Myers Type Indicator, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Testing - Clerical Research, 1940-1953 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Testing - Conference on Personnel Measurement, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Testing - Critique on Clerical Testing, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Testing - Cross Validation "Key Punch Study", 1949 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Testing - Estimated vs. Actual I.Q., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Testing - Humm - Watsworth Study, 1939-1945 (Box 3, Folder 19-22)
- Testing - Measurement, 1949-1957 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Testing - Milwaukee Plan of Aptitude Testing, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Testing - Miscellaneous, 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Testing - Prediction of Clerical Success, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Testing - Sales of Tests, 1949-1955 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Testing - Scott Paper Co, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Testing - Statistical Methods, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Testing - Test Norms, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Testing - Test Preparation Manuals, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Testing - Test Service Bulletin, 1947-1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Testing - Tests to be Developed, 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Testing - Validity, 1949-1954 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Testing - Warm - Up Test, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Testing - Wherry Test Selection Method (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Testing - Worthington Personal History Analysis, 1950-1954 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Test - Bibliography of Tests (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Test - Achievement - Blackstone Stenographic Proficiency, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Test - Achievement - California Reading Test (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Test - Achievement - California Test of English Usage (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Test - Achievement - Cooperative English Test (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Test - Achievement - Cooperative Vocabulary Test, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Test - Achievement - Iowa Silent Reading Tests, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Test - Achievement - the N.I.I.P. Clerical Test (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Test - Achievement - National Business Entrance Test, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Test - Achievement - Otis Arithmetic Reasoning Test, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Test - Achievement - Progressive Achievement Tests, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Test - Achievement - Seashore - Bennett Stenographic Test, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Test - Achievement - Test for Stenographic Skill, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Test - Achievement - Test for Typing Skill, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Test - Multi-Aptitude Battery - California Occupational Aptitude Test (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Test - Multi-Aptitude Battery - Factoried Aptitude Series, 1948-1951 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Test - Multi-Aptitude Battery - Flanagan Aptitude Classification Test, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Clerical Aptitude Test, 1943-1950 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Coding Test (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Finger Dexterity Test (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - General Clerical Test, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Hay Name Finding Test, 1949-1955 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Hay Number Perception Test, 1947-1951 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Hay Number Series Completion Test, 1949-1955 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Hay Tests for Clerical Aptitude, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Letter Cross Out Scale (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - L.O.M.A. Mathematical Test 4M, 1938-1941 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Martin Office Aptitude Tests (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Minnesota Vocational Clerical Test, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Number Cross Out Scale, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - PCI Selection Form 20, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Posting Test, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Primary Business Interests Tests, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Purdue Clerical Adaptability Test, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - SRA Clerical Aptitudes, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Short Employment Test, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Simple Posting Test, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Survey of Working Speed & Accuracy, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Test of Clerical Aptitude, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Test - Aptitude, Clerical - Work Sample I, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Test - Aptitude, Executive - O'Connor Vocabulary Test, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Test - Aptitude, Food Stores - the Store Personnel Test, 1946-1951 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Test - Aptitude, News Reporting - Reporter Situations Test, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Test - Aptitude, Selling - Sales Situations Test, 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Test - Aptitude, Selling - Salesability Exam & Analysis, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Test - Aptitude, Selling - Test of Sales Aptitude, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Test - Aptitude, Stenography - Stenogauge, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Test - Aptitude, Stenography - Stenographic Aptitude Test, 1939-1945 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- Test - Aptitude, Stenography - Turse Shorthand Aptitude Test, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- Test - Aptitude, Supervisory - How Supervise?, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Test - Aptitude, Supervisory - Test of Practical Judgment, 1942-1948 (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Test - Aptitude, White Collar - Vocational Aptitude Exam, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Test - Attitude Survey - SRA Employee Inventory, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Test - Intelligence - Army Alpha Exam, 1940-1951 (Box 4, Folder 61)
- Test - Intelligence - Army General Classification Test, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 62)
- Test - Intelligence - The Business Test, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 63)
- Test - Intelligence - California Mental Maturity Test, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 64)
- Test - Intelligence - Curtis Classification Form, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 65)
- Test - Intelligence - L.O.M.A. Test No. 1, Form A, 1936-1943 (Box 4, Folder 66)
- Test - Intelligence - Letter - Partington Adult Performance Scale, 1949-1951 (Box 4, Folder 67)
- Test - Intelligence - Placement Guide I, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 68)
- Test - Intelligence - Mill Hill Vocabulary Scale, 1938-1948 (Box 4, Folder 69)
- Test - Intelligence - Ohio State University Psychological Test, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 70)
- Test - Intelligence - Otis Self-Administering Tests, 1922-1941 (Box 4, Folder 71)
- Test - Intelligence - Personnel Classification Test, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 72)
- Test - Intelligence - Progressive Matrices, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 73)
- Test - Intelligence - SRA Non-Verbal Form, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 73a)
- Test - Intelligence - Thurstone Test of Mental Alertness, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 74)
- Test - Intelligence - Wonderlic Personnel Test, 1945-1950 (Box 4, Folder 75)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Activity Vector Analysis, 1948-1955 (Box 4, Folder 76)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - The Adjustment Inventory, 1934-1938 (Box 4, Folder 77)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Briggs - Myers type Indicator, 1944-1946 (Box 4, Folder 78)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Contact Personality Factor Test, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 79)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Executive Personality Evaluation, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - G - Z Temperament Map, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - the Group Oral Performance Test, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Humm - Wadsworth Temperament Scale, 1934-1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - IPAT Humor Test of Personality (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - An Inventory of Factors STDCR, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Industrial Inventory - E (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Neurotic Personality Factor Test, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - the Personal Audit, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - the Personality Inventory, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Personality Record, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Scorable Interview - Application Form (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Shipley - Institute of Living Scale, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Sixteen Personality Factor Test, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Social Intelligence Test (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Street Gestalt Completion Test, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - A Study of Values, 1931-1951 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Thurstone Temperament Schedule, 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Test - Personality - N.P. - Work Preference Inventory, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Test - Preparatory - Test I: The Warm Up, 1945-1955 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Test - Vocational Interests - Kuder Preference Record, 1948-1953 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Test - Vocational Interests - Occupational Interest Inventory, 1943-1946 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Test - ? (Money & Motivation) ? - The R & G Inventory, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Hay Publications - Bibliographies (Box 5, Folder 24)
- "Selecting New Employees", 1936 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Banking, December, 1936. pp. 79-80
- "Organization.", 1938 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  (unpublished) January, 1938. 5 pp
- Practical Rating Plans, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  New York: American Management Association. 11 pp
- "Payroll Control", 1937 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Banking, May, 1937. pp. 30-31
- "Philadelphia Personnel Association", 1937 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Personnel Journal, Vol. 15, No. 10, April, 1937. 4 pp
- "School, Business and Life", 1938 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Business Education Observer, Vol. 10, No. 1, November, 1938. pp. 21-24
- "The Personnel Function", 1936 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Banking, October, 1936. pp. 86-88
- "Constructing Salary Scales", 1936 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Personnel Journal, Vol. 14, No. 10, April, 1936. pp. 350-356
- How to Finance a Business, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  New York: American Management Association. 12 pp
- How to Finance Your Business, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Philadelphia: Brooke, Stokes and Company, 19 pp
- "Increasing Production and Wages by Paying Bonus,", 1917 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Industrial Management, November, 1917. pp. 184-190
- "Hiring an Advertising Assistant", 1937 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Personnel Journal, Vol. 15, No. 10, April, 1937. pp. 377-378
- "The Compa-Ratio: A Means of Control of Salary Expense", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Advanced Management, March, 1940. pp. 9-11
- Inaugurating a Test Program, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  New York: American Management Association, 1940. 12 pp.
- "Profitable Ideas for Management of Personnel", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  (a section of Business Ideas for Increasing Profits) New York: Prentice Hall, 1940. (70 pp.)
- "Banks Under Wage-Hour Act: Four Methods of Calculating Overtime Legal Under Law", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  American Banker, Vol. 105, No. 173, July 25, 1940. pp. 1 & 5
- "Man-Power Development for Trust Work", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Trusts and Estates, Vol. 70, No. 6, June, 1940. pp. 593-598
- "The Right Pay for the Job", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Banking, March, 1940. pp. 22-23
- "Wage-Salary Classification to Build Good-Will and Control Payroll Costs", 1939 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Philadelphia, November, 1939. pp. 10-11
- "Planning for Fair Salaries and Wages", 1939 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Personnel Journal, Vol. 18, No. 4, October, 1939. pp. 141-150
- "Arranging the Right Pay", 1939 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Personnel Journal, Vol. 17, No. 10, April, 1939. 7 pp
- "Pre-Selling New Internal Policies", 1939 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Executives Service Bulletin, Vol. 17, No. 4, April, 1939. pp. 5-6
- "Leadership", 1939 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Personnel, Vol. 16, No. 1, August, 1939. pp. 39-40
- "The Relationship Between Clerical Experience and Scores on the Minnesota Vocational Test for Clerical Workers", 1943 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 27, No. 4, August, 1943. pp. 311-315
- The Office Supervisor's Functions and Responsibilities, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  New York: American Management Association. 20 pp
- Punch Card Methods in Payroll Work, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  New York: American Management Association. 18 pp
- "A Successful Job Evaluation Plan", 1944 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  The Burroughs Clearing House, August, 1944. 6 pp
- "Proper Use of Personnel Departments", 1944 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  Personnel Journal, Vol. 22, No. 8, February, 1944. pp. 281-288
- "Predicting Success in Machine Bookkeeping", 1943 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 27, No. 6, December, 1943. pp. 483+.
- "Testing Clerical Applicants", 1942 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 26, No. 6, December, 1942. pp. 852-855
- "Comparison of Otis and Alpha Test Scores Made by Bank Clerks", 1942 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 26, No. 6, December, 1942. pp. 850- 851
- Establishing a Central Machine-Transcription Office, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  N.O.M.A. Forum, Vol. 17, No. 1, October, 1941. pp. 4-9
- "How We Established Written Employee Policies", 1941 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  Personnel, Vol. 18, No. 2, September, 1941. 4 pp
- Psychological Aids in the Selection of Workers, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  New York: American Management Association
- "Predicting Success in Routine Bank Work.", 1944 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  (unpublished) 8 pp
- "Bank Personnel Work Under Wartime Conditions", 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  (in three parts), Bankers Monthly, I. "Finding New Employees," December, 1942. II. "Use of Tests," January, 1943. III. "Personnel Policies," February, 1943
- "The Duties of the Office Supervisor", 1947 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Personnel Journal, Vol. 26, No. 4, October, 1947. pp. 146-149
- "The Attitude of the American Federation of Labor on Job Evaluation", 1947 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Personnel Journal, Vol. 26, No. 5, November, 1947. pp. 163-169
- "Postscript to Predicting Success in Machine Bookkeeping", 1947 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 31, No. 3, June, 1947. p. 235
- "A Program of Salary Administration", 1947 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Personnel, Vol. 24, No. 1, 1947. 15 pp
- "How to Create Salary Grades", 1947 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Personnel, Vol. 23, No. 5, 1947, 15 pp
- "Assuring Equal Pay for Equal Work", 1946 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Proceedings, National Office Management Association. 15 p
- "Salary Administration", 1946 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  National Auditgram, Vol. 22, No. 8, August, 1946. 7 pp
- "Four Methods of Establishing Factor Scales in Factor Comparison Job Evaluation", 1946 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Personnel, Vol. 23, No. 2, 1946. 11 pp
- "Procedure for Installing a Plan of Salary and Wage Management with Job Evaluation.", 1946 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  (mimeographed) February, 1946, 5 pp
- "Training the Evaluation Committee in Factor Comparison Job Evaluation", 1946 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Personnel, Vol. 23, No. 1, 1946. 14 pp
- "Characteristics of Factor Comparison Job Evaluation", 1946 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Personnel, Vol. 22, No. 6, 1946. 7 pp
- Control of Salary Expense, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  New York: American Management Association. 14 pp
- "Union-Management Cooperation in Job Evaluation", 1945 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Conference Board Management Record, June, 1945. 3 pp
- "Job Evaluation for Trust Companies", 1945 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Trusts and Estates, July, 1945. 3 pp
- "The Characteristics of Salary Grades", 1946 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Personnel, Vol. 23, No. 3, 1946. 14 pp
- "Techniques of Securing Agreement in Job Evaluation Committees", 1950 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  Personnel, January, 1950. 7 pp
- "Fit the Pay to the Job", 1950 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  Banking, October, 1950. 4 pp
- "A Warm-Up Test", 1950 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  Personnel Psychology, Vol. 3, No. 2, Summer, 1950. pp. 221-223
- "Getting the Most for Your Payroll Dollar.", 1948 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  (unpublished) September, 1948. 3 pp
- "The Application of Weber's Law to Job Evaluation Estimates", 1950 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 34, No. 2, April, 1950. pp. 102-104
- "Prediction from Selected Cutting Scores.", 1949 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  (mimeographed) June, 1949. 14 pp
- "Setting Standards of Value for Executive Compensation", 1949 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  The Controller, March, 1949. pp. 116-118.
- A Flexible Method of Salary Cost Control, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  New York: American Management Association. 8 pp
- "Creating Factor Comparison Key Scales by the Per Cent Method", 1948 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 32, No. 5, October, 1948. pp. 456-464
- "Cross Validation of Clerical Aptitude Tests", 1950 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 34, No. 3, June, 1950. pp. 153-158
- Your Pay, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Philadelphia: Edward N. Hay Associates. 13 pp
- "A Note on Small Samples", 1953 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 37, No. 6, December, 1953. p. 445
- "The Validation of Tests", 1953 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Personnel, May, 1953. 10 pp
- "What Should a Personnel Department be Doing", 1953 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Personnel Panorama, Vol. 6, No. 1, January, 1953. 3 pp
- "Validation of Tests.", 1952 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  (mimeographed) October, 1952. 7 pp
- "How You Administer Salaries Goes Deep", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Management Review, May, 1951. p. 271.
- "Some Research Findings with the Wonderlic Personnel Test", 1952 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 36, No. 5, October, 1952. pp. 344-345